#### Thirty-year-plus computing veteran looking to lead a team working on making the world better.

My experience ranges from solo coder to Silicon Valley executive, from bringup on bare metal to mobile UI, and from low-key mentoring sessions to full-bore crisis management around the world. I'm known for combining exceptional technical expertise and an outstanding breadth of knowledge with excellent communications, mentoring, and problem-solving skills.

# **Strengths**

- Architect, design, and implement robust, high-performance, scalable, secure solutions to complex problems, whether working from a clean sheet or diving into a million lines of existing source.
- Solve problems in complex systems, even while managing crisis situations.
- Communicate effectively in a wide range of situations, to a wide range of audiences.
- Provide leadership and mentoring where needed.
- Adapt readily to new technologies, while retaining what's useful in older technologies.

# **Technologies**

- Extensive experience with:
  - (in alphabetical order) C, CoffeeScript, C++, Java, JavaScript, Objective-C, Perl, Python, shell, SQL, etc.
  - iOS native development and cross-platform hybrid mobile development
  - UNIX development and administration from System III forward, notably including MacOS and Linux
  - Database and SaaS platforms (including MySQL, PostgreSQL, Parse.com, Salesforce, etc.)
  - Internetworking, including performance, security, and protocol design, using both IPv4 and IPv6
  - Internet messaging
- Familiar with Android development, Django, LISP, PHP, Ruby on Rails, etc.

### Career

# Prompt.ly, Inc. 2014-present

### **Head of Development**

- Lead the team creating a cross-platform mobile application for solopreneurs to better manage their businesses. Responsibilities include:
  - Own development of the handset application (JavaScript/HTML/CSS under Forge) and the backend server (JavaScript on Parse.com)
  - Manage the development pipeline, working with the C-suite and the product management team;
  - Keep the team working smoothly: mentor and prioritize as needed, clear obstacles where possible;
  - Create and manage processes around source control, repeatable builds, deployment, and updates; and
  - Ensure security and performance of handset/server communications.
- Individually design, implement, and support tools and code as needed. Examples include:
  - Rewrote much of the core of the handset application;
  - Moved the application from callback architecture to promises, dramatically improving code reusability;
  - Created the module system that allows code sharing between handset and server; and
  - Created and maintained the build system.

## **Basis Technology Corporation**

2011-2014

#### **Principal Software Engineer, Digital Forensics**

- Provided technical leadership for a team creating tools for forensic analysis focused on mobile telephones.
  - Examples include SQLite data recovery, Symbian data logging, etc.
- Individually designed, implemented, and supported tools as needed. Examples include:
  - Decryption/extraction of iOS device backups;
  - Forensic analysis of iOS data using a graphical Macintosh application;
  - Reverse engineering dumb phone data; and
  - Cross-platform GUI applications to normalize, manipulate, and compare cell phone data.

## iFan Media Corporation

2010-2011

### iPhone Development Lead

- Developed iFan Media's mobile social media application platform, which enabled quickly and easily producing custom-branded iPhone applications from a single code base.
  - Designed and implemented support for audio streaming, realtime chat, interaction with host(s), offers/ deals, calendars, service requests, Facebook, Twitter, RSS news feeds, and runtime reconfiguration.
  - Created tooling for automated builds of multiple branded applications from a single source base, from compilation through packaging applications for the Apple App Store.
  - Design and implement runtime configuration, allowing changes to be pushed from iFan Media's servers without client code changes.

#### **Chief Security Officer**

• Ensured that iFan's business practices and products adequately protected users' personal information, and that iFan's systems adequately protected themselves from the hostile Internet.

# Mirapoint Software, Inc.

2007-2010

### Vice President, Field Technical Services

2008-2010

- Led the Field Technical Services group, comprising technical pre-sales for the Americas and professional services worldwide, responsible for ensuring the success of customer deployments.
  - Improved post-sales supportability of new installations by establishing more consistent guidelines for pre-sales efforts and improving working relations with international divisions.
  - Maintained a 100% success rate for deployments worldwide.

#### Member of Technical Staff

2007-2008

• Led Mirapoint's Release Engineering group, with responsibility for releases, source code control system (Perforce), and engineering build tooling, including substantial tools development efforts.

Mirapoint, Inc. 1999-2007

#### Member of Technical Staff

- Mentored and led a group of junior engineers in India, forming them into a functioning engineering team.
- Contributed significant functionality and performance improvements to all the infrastructure components of Mirapoint's Messaging Operating System (MOS), especially the email transport system, including:
  - Created a new bootloader to support new hardware;
  - Designed and implemented IMAP folder sharing across multiple message stores;
  - Designed and implemented Mirapoint's SSL support, used everywhere in the system.

## **Cendant Internet Engineering**

1996-1999

#### **Systems Programmer and Managing Architect**

- Led the Core Development group, responsible for the infrastructure supporting Cendant's e-commerce platform.
- Designed and led the implementation of the core middleware engine that mediated access from Cendant's web applications, supporting upgrades and rollbacks with zero downtime under full production load.

*Teradyne, Inc.* 1993-1996

#### **Design Engineer**

- Contributed significant functionality to the infrastructure components of Teradyne's automated test systems. Examples include:
  - Designed and implemented changes to allow the tester to take full advantage of multiple CPUs for DSP while retaining binary compatibility with earlier versions (patented).
  - Designed and implemented RPC mechanisms to allow the tester to be controlled by an external system.
  - Designed and implemented a multithreaded database search engine supporting regular expressions, Boolean operations, and multiple output formats.

# First Albany Corporation

1988-1991

#### **Systems Analyst**

• Designed and implemented a full-screen menu-driven interface to make UNIX systems accessible to financial traders.

### Digitech Communcations, Inc.

1983-1987

#### **Software Engineer**

- Designed and implemented a partial PL/1 compiler to take over the function of broken hardware in the company's revenue stream.
- Designed and implemented a full-screen telephone billing data editor used to prepare telephony systems for delivery to customers.

Personal Projects ongoing

- Developed KAsset, a digital asset identification system that can uniquely identify assets while preserving local ordering and grouping, preventing name collisions, and still permitting publishing using short, easy-to-remember names. Currently manages tens of thousands of photographs and other important data.
- Developed and open-sourced fKeys, the first MacOS X keyboard remapper to support MacOS X 10.4. Supported its user base and assisted developers incorporating its code into other tools. Although active development stopped in 2008, it continued to work with all Macintoshes and MacOS X through Snow Leopard.
- Developed and open-sourced FMI, a character-mode IMAP mailreader designed to minimize waiting time for its user, even with slow, high-latency network links and very large email folders. FMI was my primary UNIX mailreader for some five years.

# **Education**

BS Computer & Systems Engineering, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1993